projectopus.com 2008-12-18

# Privacy Statement | Project Opus

**Information Collection and Use by Project Opus**  
Project Opus collects user submitted information such as name, email address, and age to authenticate users and to send notifications to those users relating to the Project Opus service. Project Opus also collects other profile data including but not limited to: personal interests, gender, age, education and occupation in order to assist users in finding and communicating with each other.

Project Opus also logs non-personally-identifiable information including IP address, profile information, aggregate user data, and browser type, from users and visitors to the site This data is used to manage the website, track usage and improve the website services. This non-personally-identifiable information may be shared with third-parties to provide more relevant services and advertisements to members. User IP addresses are recorded for security and monitoring purposes.

User Profile information including members' pictures and first names are displayed to people in order to facilitate user interaction in the Project Opus music community. User's email address is not shared or displayed to people within a user's personal network. Users within a Project Opus network communicate on Project Opus with each other internally through the Project Opus service, without disclosing their email addresses. Users' full names are never directly revealed to other members. To facilitate searching on the Website, Project Opus allows users to search for other members using first and last name, band or artist name or company name.  
We may also use a user's email address to send updates, a newsletter or news regarding the Service. Users may choose not to receive email of this type by changing their "notification" setting to "Do not send me notification emails" in the user "Account Settings".

From time to time, Project Opus or a partner, may sponsor a promotion or contest on Project Opus. Users may be asked to provide personal information including name, email address or home address or to answer questions in order to participate. We may transfer personal information to certain ad partners that you have explicitly requested to receive information from. It will be clear at the point of collection who is collecting the personal information and whose privacy statement will apply.

**Links**  
Project Opus contains links to sites. Project Opus is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When linking to another site a user should read the privacy policy stated on that site. Our privacy policy only governs information collected on Project Opus.

**Chat Rooms, Journals and WebLogs, Message Boards, Classifieds and Public Forums**  
Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily post public information to Journals, WebLogs, Message Boards, Classifieds or any other Public Forums that that information can be accessed by the public and can in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications.

**Correcting/Updating or Removing Information**  
Project Opus users may modify or remove any of their personal information at any time by logging into their account and accessing features such as Edit Profile and Account Info.

**Security**  
Project Opus member accounts are secured by member-created passwords Project Opus takes precautions to ensure that member account information is kept private. We use reasonable measures to protect member information that is stored within our database, and we restrict access to member information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer service personnel and technical staff. Please note that we cannot guarantee the security of member account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of member information at any time

**Sharing and Disclosure of Information Project Opus Collects**  
Except as otherwise described in this privacy statement, Project Opus will not disclose personal information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary: (1) to conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process received by Project Opus, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (2) to enforce the Project Opus Terms of Use Agreement or to protect our rights; or (3) to protect the safety of members of the public and users of the service. Project Opus reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of Project Opus or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest.
